<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Jiawen Huang</title>
    <link>http://www.huang-jiawen.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Jiawen Huang</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://www.huang-jiawen.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Memory and prediction in the 4-in-a-row game</title>
      <link>http://www.huang-jiawen.com/projects/4-in-a-row/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.huang-jiawen.com/projects/4-in-a-row/</guid>
      <description>Schema-based predictive eye-movements support sequential memory encoding When forming a memory of an experience that is unfolding over time, we can use our schematic knowledge about the world (constructed based on many prior episodes) to predict what will transpire. We developed a novel paradigm to study how the development of a complex schema influences predictive processes during perception and impacts sequential memory. Participants learned to play a novel board game (“4-in-a-row”) across six training sessions, and repeatedly performed a memory test in which they watched and recalled sequences of moves from the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Neural representation of memory during Method of Loci</title>
      <link>http://www.huang-jiawen.com/projects/writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.huang-jiawen.com/projects/writing/</guid>
      <description>Image generated with Stable diffusion based on connecting the word &amp;ldquo;elephant&amp;rdquo; with the locus &amp;ldquo;couch&amp;rdquo; from a participant&amp;rsquo;s recall.
Neural representation of memory during Method of Loci In this ongoing study, we train a group of novices to learn the ancient technique called Method of Loci (aka. Memory Palace, Roman Room) and scan them 3 times over 4 weeks. Participants build a personal memory palace (a &amp;lsquo;cognitive map&amp;rsquo;) and come in to use it for remembering a list of words in fMRI scanner.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naturalistic Neuroimaging Database</title>
      <link>http://www.huang-jiawen.com/projects/nndb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.huang-jiawen.com/projects/nndb/</guid>
      <description>Scene from 500 days of summer, a movie that I really get to hate very much because I watched it so many times while scanning / working on some annotation of the project&amp;hellip;
A naturalistic neuroimaging database for understanding the brain using ecological stimuli Neuroimaging has advanced our understanding of human psychology using reductionist stimuli that often do not resemble information the brain naturally encounters. It has improved our understanding of the network organization of the brain mostly through analyses of ‘resting-state’ data for which the functions of networks cannot be verifiably labelled.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
